Pivot tables summarize an aggregate all in one step.
数据透视表一步到位地聚合汇总
In a baseball dataset,
在棒球数据集中
we see several rows of each team and several rows for each playing position.
我们看到每个球队有好几行 每个位置也有好几行
A pivot will let us group all the teams and all the positions.
数据透视表可以对所有球队和所有位置分组
Select the dataset and go to insert pivot table.
选中数据集 然后转到插入数据透视表
The default is to put it in a new sheet and that's what we want.
默认情况下是将结果放入新的工作表中 我们正希望如此
Now, we have some drag and drop dialogs.
现在是一些拖拽对话框
We're looking for the rows and columns to be
我们要寻找的是球队和位置
the grouped categories of teams and positions,
分组后类别对应的行和列
and the cells in between to be the aggregations of
以及分组之间聚合信息的单元格
those groups such as a count of how many pitchers on each team.
例如每个球队有多少位 Pitcher (投手)
So let's slide the team values to rows and here they are now listed,
因此将 Team 拖动到行上 现在列出来了
one for each unique team,
每个唯一球队一行
and the playing positions to columns and here they are, unique positions listed.
将 Position 拖动到列上 列出了所有的唯一位置
Now, we have salaries and names left to choose from for the aggregation.
现在有薪资和姓名可以选择来进行汇总
Since we just want to know how many players in each position for each team,
因为我们只想知道每个球队每个位置有多少名球员
it makes sense to just add the names.
因此只需将姓名数量相加即可
The default aggregation function is count.
默认的聚合函数是计数
Now, we can look at the table and see how many players
现在可以查看表格并了解
in each position each team has on their roster,
每个球队每个位置有多少名球员
and how many players are on each team,
以及每个球队有多少名球员
and how many catchers,
整个大联盟里有多少名
first baseman and pitchers there are in the entire league.
Catcher (捕手)、First Baseman (一垒手) 和 Pitchers (投手)
We just found all of that out in a few clicks.
只需点击几下就能知道所有这些信息了
What if we wanted to know how much money each team spends on which positions?
如果想知道每个球队在各个位置球员上 花费多少成本呢？
In that case our rows and columns can stay the same,
这样的话 行和列可以保持不变
but the data we need is the salaries,
但是所需的数据是薪资
so replace the names with the salary information.
因此将姓名替换为薪资信息
Nothing really changed because we're still counting
其实没什么变化
the number of salaries not summing them.
因为我们依然是计数薪资数量 而不是求和
To use a different aggregation function,
要使用其他聚合函数
click the pull down menu and select field settings.
点击下拉菜单并选择字段设置
There are several that we learned about earlier.
我们之前学习了几个函数
Select the Sum aggregation.
选择求和汇总方式
Now we have the salary sums for each team in position,
现在得出了每个球队每个位置的薪资之和
as well as the subtotals and the grand total.
以及小计和总计
To make this more readable,
为了使数据更易读懂
select the whole area and change the data type to either accounting or currency.
选择整个区域并将数据类型改为会计专用或货币
Okay, now you try.
现在该你来试试了